A Guide to the Haight-Barlow Family Collection, 1791-1987
Virginia Room, Fairfax County Public Library
- Series 1: Family Correspondence, 1816-1904
  - Maria L. Barlow to James P. Barlow, 1863 October 18 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Maria L. Barlow to Jacob H. Barlow, 1863 October 19 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - James P. Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1863 October 21 (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to James P. Barlow, 1863 October 22 (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - James P. Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1863 October 28 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Alexander Haight to Maria L. Barlow, 1863 October 28 (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to James P. Barlow, 1863 November 1 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - J.S. Haight to Maria L. Barlow, 1863 November 11 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - James P. Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1863 November 3 (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to Sue, 1863 November 4 (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to James P. Barlow, 1863 November 6 (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - James P. Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1863 November 11 (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to James P. Barlow, 1863 November 12 (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - James P. Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1863 November 13 (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - James P. Barlow to Jacob H. Barlow, 1863 November 22 (Box 2, Folder 92)
  - James P. Barlow to Jacob H. Barlow, 1863 December 18 (Box 2, Folder 93)
  - Maria L. Barlow to Jacob H. Barlow, 1863 December 27 (Box 2, Folder 94)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to Sue, 1863 December 31 (Box 2, Folder 95)
  - James P. Barlow to ? [partial letter], 1863 (Box 2, Folder 96)
  - James P. Barlow to ? [partial letter], 1863 (Box 2, Folder 97)
  - James P. Barlow to Maria L. Barlow [partial letter], 1863 (Box 2, Folder 98)
  - J.S. Haight to Maria L. Barlow, 1865 January 16 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - J. Howley & Co.(?) to Jacob H. Barlow, 1865 January 16 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - J.W. Ware to James P. Barlow, 1866 January 21 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Frederick Douglass to Miss Barnes (probably the future Nettie W. Barlow), 1866 June 9 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to James P. Barlow, 1866 June 16 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - E.L. Barlow to James P. Barlow?, 1867 January 7 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Maria L. Barlow to Nettie W. Barlow, 1870 April 11 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - James P. Barlow to Jacob H. Barlow, 1870? April 11 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to James P. Barlow, 1870 April 13 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - J.S. Ganter(?) to Stephen Shear, 1870 September 12 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to James P. Barlow, 1873 October 8 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Joseph Barnes to Nettie W. Barlow, 1875 April 13 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Maria L. Barlow to Jacob H. Barlow, 1877 March 5 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - John McGill? to Maria L. Barlow, 1879 June 18 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Carroll to "Sister", 1879 November 28 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Merton C. Holman to Mr. Barlow, c. 1879 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Gorman & Pettit, Alexandria Boiler Works to Maria L. Barlow, 1882 September 29 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - O.E. Hine to Maria L. Barlow, 1883 June 9 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - O.E. Hine to Maria L. Barlow, 1883 July 30 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Gorman & Pettit, Alexandria Boiler Works to Maria L. Barlow, 1883 July 31 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - L. Haight to Maria L. Barlow, 1886 November 18 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - ? to Maria L. Barlow, 1887 April 25 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Maria L. Barlow to "Children", 1887 July 4 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - I.A. Chandler to Maria L. Barlow, 1887 November 6 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1887 November 13 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1887 December 20 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - S.A. Coe to Maria L. Barlow, 1888 January 19 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Nettie W. Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1888 August 1 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Nettie W. Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1888 December 6 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Nettie W. Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1888 December 16 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Nettie W. Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1888 December 23 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - J. Carrol Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1889 January 20 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Nettie W. Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1889 January 21 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Jane S. Haight to Maria L. Barlow, 1889 February 1 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - S.E. Shear and Lillie ? To Maria L. Barlow, 1889 February 12 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Jane S. Haight to Maria L. Barlow, 1889 March 18 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Jacob H. Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1889 April 22 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Jane S. Haight to Maria L. Barlow, 1889 May 24 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Rep. John H. Ketcham to Maria L. Barlow, 1889 July 13 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence, Allison Butts, attorney to Maria L. Barlow, Nettie W. Barlow and Jacob H. Barlow (re: J. Haviland Haight estate), 1902-1904 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - L. Haight to Maria L. Barlow, ? Aprl 21 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - L. Haight to Maria L. Barlow, ? July 29 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Maria L. Barlow? To Nettie W. Barlow, ? March 12 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Maria L. Barlow to "Children", ? August 19 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Maria L. Barlow to "Children", ? November 22 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Maria L. Barlow to Lou, ? March 20 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Nettie W. Barlow to ?, Undated (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Unknown letter [partial letter], Undated (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Envelopes, Jacob H. Barlow, 1887-1903, Undated (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Envelopes, James P. Barlow, Undated (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Envelopes, Maria L. Barlow, 1884, Undated (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Envelopes, Nettie Barlow, Undated (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Envelope, Alexander Haight, Undated (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Envelopes, Susan R. Worley, Undated (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Calling card, Isaac H. Bailey, Undated (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Calling card, Mr. and Mrs. Jacob Haight, Undated (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Calling card, Maria B. Haight, Undated (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Calling card, Charlotte M. O'Neil, Undated (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Photocopies, Haight-Barlow papers, Undated (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Microfilm, Haight-Barlow papers, Undated (Box 8)
- Series 2: Personal Writings and Items, c. 1830s-1881
  - Benjamin Mitchell testimony, 1832? (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Religious essay, Samuel Clement, c. 1830s (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Report cards, Jacob H. Barlow, Springdale Boarding School, 1859-1861 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Compositions, Jacob H. Barlow, c. 1860-1861 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Book, "The Day After Death" by Mrs. Cora L. V. Richmond, Boston: 1881 [inscribed "Nellie W. Barlow, Chantilly, Va"], 1881 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Autograph book, Nettie W. Barlow, 1866-1881 (Box 6)
  - Pouch containing 3 rocks, Undated (Box 8)
- Series 3: Deeds, 1838-1883
  - Deed, Jasper Murdock and Julia Murdock to James P. Barlow, 1838 February 12 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Deed, William H. Pells to James P. Barlow, 1838 August 15 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Deed, Moses M. Vail to James P. Barlow, 1846 December 1 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Extract from Gabriel Fox's estate division, 1847 November (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Deed, Jacob Haight and Amy Haight to Maria L. Barlow, 1851 July 28 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Deed, James P. Barlow and Maria L. Barlow to Edwin Barlow, 1853 September 15 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Deed, Jacob Haight to Maria L. Barlow and James P. Barlow, 1855 May 30 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Deed, Alexander Haight to Maria L. Barlow, 1855 June 18 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Agreement, James P. Barlow and Reuben Simpson, 1860 January 1 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Contract, James P. Barlow to Stephen Shear and Conrad Shear [sale of Sully farm], 1869 September 14 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Agreement, James P. Barlow to Stephen Shear and Conrad Shear, 1869 September 17 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Deed, Stephen Shear and Conrad Sheer to Daniel K. Hauxhurst, 1869 December 25 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Survey, James P. Barlow house lot, 1871 April 13 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Survey, Alexander Haight to James P. Barlow mill lot, 1871 December 16 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Deed, Alexander Haight and Phebe Haight to Maria L. Barlow, 1872 March 25 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Deed, Alexander Haight and Phebe Haight to James P. Barlow, 1872 March 25 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Last Will & Testament, James P. Barlow, 1874 January 10 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Agreement, James P. Barlow and J.W. Taylor, 1875 May 5 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Warranty Deed, James P. Barlow to Maria L. Barlow, 1876 December 11 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Deed, Alexander Haight and Phebe Haight to Maria L. Barlow, 1879 October 23 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Deed, Maria L. Barlow to Jacob H. Barlow, 1880 June 8 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Deed, Maria L. Barlow to O.E. Hine, 1883 September 3 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Blank receipt, Frederick Bostwick, Clerk of the Court, Dutchess County, New York, Undated (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Envelopes, Vernon W. Barlow's descriptions of deed contents, Undated (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Series 4: Financial Records, 1791-1934
  - Account book, Ten Eyck family, 1791-1853 (Box 6)
  - "Sully" Receipt book, James P. Barlow, 1848-1873 (Box 6)
  - Receipts, James P. Barlow, 1856-1859 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Receipts, James P. Barlow, 1861-1864 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Receipts, James P. Barlow, Tax Collector's, 1865-1866 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Receipts, James P. Barlow, Adams Express Company, 1866 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Receipts, James P. Barlow, 1866-1869 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Blank checks, Riggs & Co., Washington, D.C., c.1860s (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Account book, James P. Barlow, 1870-1873 (Box 6)
  - Receipts, James P. Barlow, 1870-1875 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Policy, Maria L. Barlow, Mutual Fire Insurance Company of Loudoun County, 1877 June 1 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Receipt, Merton C. Holman and Maria L. Barlow to L. Barrtell, 1878 March 24 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Receipt, Gorman & Pettit, Alexandria Boiler Works to Mr. Troth, 1878 October 8 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Receipt, Alexander Haight, 1880 property tax, 1880 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Policy, Maria L. Barlow, Mutual Fire Insurance Company of Loudoun County, 1884 July 1 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Account book, Nettie W. Barlow, Bank of Blue Rapids, 1886-1887 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Receipts, Jacob H. Barlow, Kansas Mutual Life Association, 1891-1892 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Account book, Jacob H. Barlow, Merchants Bank, Waterville, Kansas, 1903 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Receipt, C.H. McNider, Head Banker, Modern Woodmen of America to Jacob H. Barlow, 1907 October 3 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Account book, Gertrude B. Failyer, First National Bank, Manhattan, Kansas, 1920-1934 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Receipts, James P. Barlow, Undated (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Receipt envelope, James P. Barlow, Undated (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Accounting notes, Undated (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Business card, New York & Washington Steamship Co., Undated (Box 4, Folder 45)
- Series 5: Blue Rapids, Kansas Business Records, 1874-1891
  - Cook, Chandler & Barlow - Promissory note, Cook, Chandler & Barlow to Nettie W. Barlow, 1874 October 24 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Cook, Chandler & Barlow - Advertisement, c. 1870s (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Cook, Chandler & Barlow - Accounting note, c. 1870s (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Barlow & McGrew - Blank receipts, 1886 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Barlow & McGrew - Receipt, Parks, Eckel to Barlow & McGrew, 1886 March 1 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Barlow & McGrew - Release Deed, George Rix to Nettie W. Barlow, Jacob H. Barlow, Elizannah McGrew and Harland McGrew, 1886 March 1 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Barlow & McGrew - Agreement to Convey, Barlow & McGrew to J.E. Andrews and D. H. Miller, 1886 October 27 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Barlow & McGrew - Article of Copartnership, 1886 October 27 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Barlow & McGrew - Promissory note, D.H. Miller and M.L. Duncan to Barlow & McGrew, 1886 November 24 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - M.L. Duncan & Co. - Partners statements, M.L. Duncan, D.H. Miller, J.H. Barlow, 1886-1892 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - M.L. Duncan & Co. - Deed, Elizannah McGrew and Harland McGrew to M.L. Duncan, 1888 January 18 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - M.L. Duncan & Co. - Letter, Jacob H. Barlow to M.L. Duncan & Co. (RE: Sale of mill), 1891 March 24 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - M.L. Duncan & Co. - Accounting page, c. 1890s (Box 4, Folder 58)
- Series 6: Newspapers, 1864-1962
  - Virginia State Journal; Alexandria, Va., 1864 September 23 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Daily Morning Chronicle; Washington, D.C., 1865 April 4 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Obituary, Maria L. Barlow, 1903 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - The Sunday Star; Washington, D.C. (re: Dulles), 1962 November 11 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - "Dulles Passengers Land In Historic U.S. Area", Washington Star; Washington, D.C., 1962 November 22 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - The Manhattan Mercury; Manhattan, Kansas (re: Dulles), 1962 November 18 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - "Lilacs, Purple and White" by Mrs. Nettie Barlow, Undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Series 7: Family History Papers, 1907-1974
  - Haight-Barlow family history, Undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Haight-Barlow genealogical data, 1907-1930 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Riley Family - bible records and photographs, 1969, Undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Riley Family Genealogy - notes and family history, 1970-1974 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Ten Eyck Family Genealogy - notes and family history, Undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Ten Eyck Family Genealogy - notes and clippings, 1967, Undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Series 8: Vernon & Martha Barlow Papers on Sully Plantation, 1938-1987
  - Correspondence, Gertrude B. Failyer to Vernon and Martha Barlow [includes photos of Sully], 1938-1954 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Letter, Martha Barlow to Lindsay Nolting [includes photos of Sully], 1954 April 1 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, Vernon W. Barlow with Luke Chaney, 1962 November (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Summary of Haight-Barlow letters compiled by Martha S. Barlow, 1967 August (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, Vernon and Martha Barlow with Fairfax County Park Authority and R.E. Wagstaff, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Letter, Dorothy Barlow Langham to Vernon and Martha Barlow [includes photos of Sully], 1968 July 2 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, Martha Barlow with Louise M. Ryder, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Sully postcards and booklet, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, Vernon and Martha Barlow with Robert S. Gamble, 1971-1974 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, Vernon and Martha Barlow with Sully Foundation Ltd., Robert S. Gamble, and Fairfax County Park Authority, 1974-1979 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Sully Plantation Dedication, 1975-1979 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Photos and negatives, Sully, 1987, Undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Notes, Undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Series 9: Photographs, c. 1850s - 1882
  - Jacob Haight, Undated (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Amy Clement Haight, Undated (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Maria Haight Barlow, Undated (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Maria Haight Barlow, Undated (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - James P. Barlow, Undated (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Jacob Haight Barlow, Undated (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Jacob Haight Barlow, Undated (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Jacob Haight Barlow, Undated (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Nettie W. Barlow, Undated (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Unidentified child, Undated (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Index card of photo identifications, Undated (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - James P. Barlow [4" x 4.5" daguerreotype] [restricted access due to fragile condition], Undated (Box 7)
  - James P. Barlow? [3" x 3.5" daguerreotype] [restricted access due to fragile condition], Undated (Box 7)
  - Jacob Haight [3" x 3.5" daguerreotype] [restricted access due to fragile condition], Undated (Box 7)
  - Charles Haight [3" x 3.5" daguerreotype] [restricted access due to fragile condition], Undated (Box 7)
  - Amy Clement Haight [3" x 3.5" daguerreotype] [restricted access due to fragile condition], Undated (Box 7)
  - Maria Barlow [3" x 3.5" daguerreotype] [restricted access due to fragile condition], Undated (Box 7)
  - Jacob H. Barlow [3" x 3.5" daguerreotype] [restricted access due to fragile condition], Undated (Box 7)
  - Jacob H. Barlow [3" x 3.5" daguerreotype] [restricted access due to fragile condition], Undated (Box 7)
  - Alonzo Haight [3" x 3.5" daguerreotype] [restricted access due to fragile condition], Undated (Box 7)
  - Unidentified man [3" x 3.5" daguerreotype] [restricted access due to fragile condition], Undated (Box 7)
  - Unidentified woman [3" x 3.5" daguerreotype] [restricted access due to fragile condition], Undated (Box 7)
  - Unidentified boy [2.5" x 3" daguerreotype] [restricted access due to fragile condition], Undated (Box 7)
  - Photo album, "To Gertie from Fred. 1882", 1882 (Box 8)